Joachim Tan

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

I am currently a Penultimate Computer Science Major at the University Of Exeter. My interests are in Full Stack Development and Quantitative Trading.

I have always been interested in the inner workings of websites and applications. I wrote my first few programs in **Python** guided by a book that my parents had bought. The time spent working on them brought me much joy.

I had my first formal coding class when I enrolled in Singapore Polytechnic. I had so much fun doing school projects that I took on my own side projects, making telegram bots and coding a system in C++ that would record my online shop sales. The experience made me fall in love with the process of building products that improve our lives.

During my National Service, I continued pursuing my interest by taking online courses on **SEO**, **Django**, **Figma & React**. These skills helped me build my own website and host my expense tracker telegram bot using **Heroku**.



Hello@JoachimStanislaus.com



<u>JoachimStanislaus.com</u>



<u>JoachimStanislaus</u>



<u>JoachimStanislaus</u>



REFERENCES

Shaun Goh, Lecturer shaun_goh@sp.edu.sg Regina Moh, Senior Talent Acquisition Partner reginamohhy@gmail.com

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Intern , UBS Jun 2023 - Present

- Build a new trading platform.

Backend Developer, Hatless Studio Apr 2023 - Present Web Designer, SG Criminal Case Summary Repository Dec 2022 - Present

- Provide and propose technological solutions for organisational needs.

- Manage & update site.

Technology Director , United Kingdom Singapore Students Council Nov 2022 - Present

- Manage & Update site.

Co-Founder & Full-Stack Developer, BridgeTheGap Jul 2022 - Present

- Tools: HTML, CSS, Javascript

- Co-Founded BridgeTheGap a non-profit organisation to give disadvantaged youths access to tech education in Singapore

- Led & Developed the website.

Data Analyst , SG Enable

May 2022 - Sept

2022

- Tools: Python, Openpyxl, Pandas, PyQt5.

- Lead, Create & Develop desktop software to generate graphs and automate data collection & data sorting. Improving productivity and reducing visualisation time by 50%.
- Perform Data Analytics to gain further insights, predict trends & sudden spikes in assistance requests to better prepare infrastructure to meet sudden demand.

Instructor, Little Coder

May 2022 - Present

2022- May 2024

- 700+ Hours Taught, 80+ Students Aged 5-16
- Languages: Python, Java, Lua, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS
- Involved in Curriculum Development, Teach and conduct coding, STEM and technology related classes and programs.

EDUCATION

Bsc Computer Science, University Of Exeter

- Entry Into 2nd Year.

- Co-Founder of the UK Singapore STEM Society(UKSSS)

- Led & Developed the website.

Diploma in Computer Engineering, Singapore Polytechnic 2017-2020

- Vice Captain & Treasurer of the Waterpolo Team

PROJECTS

HackUPC 2023 (Won Category Prize)

Full-Stack Developer

- Built Mikasa.tech an Al Powered Apartment Recommendation Platform

University Of Exeter Computer Science Department Hackathon 2022

Full-Stack Developer

- Won the Academics round, the task was to produce an art piece that represents the University of Exeter.
- Placed 2nd in the Computer Science Student Reps Round, the task was to solve a collection of Python Puzzles worth different points based on their difficulty.

JP Morgan Code For Good Hackathon - Glasgow 2022

Full-Stack Developer

Climate Hack Hackathon 2022

Team Leader, Technical Lead

SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, C++, Java, VBA, Lua

Tools: Figma, DJango, Git, Bulma, Bootstrap